On commission of the USSR State Committee
of TV and Radio Broadcasting
KIEVNAUCHFILM
Artistic Animation Association
Based on the fairy tale by Lewis Carroll
ALICE IN WONDERLAND
Part 1
The author of this fairy tale is Lewis Carroll,
an able mathematician, logician and linguist.
He wrote it in the middle of the 19th century
while taking walks in the vicinity of Oxford,
along the bank of the River Thames.
He wrote it at the request
of the little girls who were his good friends.
Lewis Carroll had written a strange tale.
Everything in it is like in a fairy tale,
and yet it doesn't look at all like a fairy tale.
So, Alice got tired of sitting on the bank,
and of having nothing to do.
She peeped into the book,
but it had no pictures or conversations in it.
Her thoughts were slow and disconnected,
for the hot day made her sleepy.
I shall be late! Oh, dear! I shall be too late!
The Duchess will be furious!
She will be just savage!
Only now Alice realized that she had
never before seen a rabbit with a watch
and a waistcoat pocket to take it out of.
Burning with curiosity, she ran after it.
After such a fall as this,
I shall think nothing of tumbling downstairs!
How brave they'll all think me at home!
Why, I wouldn't say anything about it
even if I fell off the roof.
Either the well was very deep,
or Alice fell very slowly,
for she had plenty of time to look about her,
and to wonder what was going to happen next.
Excuse me, sir, can you tell me
how many miles I've fallen by this time?
I must be getting somewhere
near the center of the earth.
That would be four thousand miles down, I think.
I wonder if I shall fall right through the earth!
How funny it'll be to see the people
that walk with their heads downward!
What's their name? The Antipathies, I think...
No. No, the Antipodes!
Down and down Alice went.
“Dinah'll miss me very much
tonight,” she thought.
Dinah was her cat.
Oh, Dinah, I wish you were down here with me!
There are no mice in the air, I'm afraid,
but you might catch a gnat.
But do cats eat gnats, I wonder?
Oh, no, do gnats eat cats?
Oh, my whiskers! Oh, my poor ears!
The Duchess will never forgive me for being late.
She will be savage!
When Alice thought it over afterward,
it occurred to her that she
ought to have wondered at this.
But at the time it all seemed quite natural.
And Alice went after
the White Rabbit like the wind.
But the White Rabbit was no longer to be seen.
Alice found herself in a long hall.
Alice decided that the key
might belong to the door.
But, alas!
Either the lock was too large,
or the key was too small,
but it would not open that door.
To Alice's great delight,
the key fitted this door!
Oh, how she longed to get out of here!
But she could not even get
her head through the hole.
And even if my head would go through, it would
be of very little use without my shoulders.
Drink me.
Alice knew that some unpleasant things
had happened to children,
all because they would not
remember three rules.
They were very simple rules.
That a red-hot poker will burn you
if you hold it too long.
That if you cut your finger very deeply
with a knife it usually bleeds.
That if you drink much
from a bottle marked “poison”,
it is almost certain to disagree
with you sooner or later.
Alice had never forgotten that last rule.
However, since this bottle was not marked
“poison” , Alice ventured to taste it.
What a curious feeling!
I must be shutting up like a telescope.
Eat me.
Alice saw that her feet were getting so far off.
Another moment, and they will be out of sight.
Goodbye, feet! Oh, my poor little feet!
I wonder who will put on
your shoes and stockings for you now?
I'm sure I shan't be able!
All right, I'll send them
a new pair of shoes every Christmas.
Oh, dear! What nonsense I'm talking!
If you please, sir...
Dear, dear! How queer everything is today!
If I am not myself,
then who in the world am I?
Ah, that's the great puzzle...
Let's try to remember Geography.
London is the capital of Paris.
And Paris is the capital of Ro... Rome.
No, that's all wrong.
I'll better try and say a poem.
This is the house that Bug built.
This is the singer
That's kept in the pantry
In the house that Bug built.
This is the cheerful Empress
That bites at the singer
That's kept in the pantry
In the house that Bug built.
No, those are not the right words.
Who am I, then?
Oh, that's because of that magic fan!
Imagine that because of some thing,
you can grow so small
and just shrink away altogether!
No, no! I must get out of here.
I wish I could grow a little larger.
And then I'll find my way to that lovely garden.
It was really a good idea.
Alice knew that in order to grow larger
one had to eat or drink something.
But there was nothing around
that would suit that purpose.
♪ O Wonderland, O Wonderland, ♪
Screenplay:
Ye. Zagdansky
♪ Where anything has its way. ♪
Consultant:
N. Demurova
♪ You grow up without end, ♪
Lyrics:
V. Levin
Director:
Ye. Pruzhansky
♪ Then back you shrink away. ♪
Art Directors:
I. Smirnova, H. Umansky
♪ Or where your feet, just in a flop, ♪
Camera:
A. Mukhin
♪ Having lengthened quite a bit, ♪
Composer:
Ye. Ptichkin
♪ Would walk and walk, and never stop, ♪
Sound:
I. Moizhes
♪ When you just want to sit. ♪
Animators:
N. Marchenkova, M. Titov
N. Churilova, A. Pedan
Voices:
M. Neyolova, R. Plyatt, V. Nevinny
♪ In Wonderland, one thing is tough. ♪
♪ There's always one concern: ♪
Featured music by:
O. Respighi and L. Boccherini
♪ If you're walking down a wrong path, ♪
Editor:
S. Kutsenko
♪ Will you ever return? ♪
Executive Producer:
Ye. Dubenko
♪ If you're walking down a wrong path, ♪
End of Part 1
♪ Will you ever return? ♪
© Kiev Popular Science Film Studio 1981
On commission of the USSR State Committee
of TV and Radio Broadcasting
KIEVNAUCHFILM
Artistic Animation Association
Based on the fairy tale by Lewis Carroll
ALICE IN WONDERLAND
Part 2
Alice was getting so used
to queer things happening
that she was not at all surprised
at this encounter.
The Caterpillar was quietly smoking
a long hookah,
taking not the smallest notice of anything else.
You...
Who are you?
I hardly know, ma'am, just at present.
I know who I was when I got up this morning,
but I changed so often since.
What do you mean? Explain yourself.
I'm afraid I can't,
because I'm not myself, you see.
I don't see.
I can't understand it myself.
Being so many different sizes in a day!
You see, everything's moving somewhere
and turns into something.
What are you not content with?
I keep getting small when I need to be large.
And the other way round.
It's very uncomfortable.
One side will make you grow taller.
The other side will make you grow shorter.
One side of what?
The other side of what?
Of the mushroom.
Alice was looking at the mushroom, and tried
to make out which were the two sides of it.
As it was perfectly round,
she found this a very difficult question.
And now which is which?
Now there will be less of that stupid uncertainty!
Dear Cheshire Puss, would you tell me, please,
which way I ought to go from here?
And where do you want to get to?
I don't much care where
so long as I get somewhere.
Then it doesn't matter which way you go.
You're sure to get somewhere
if you only walk long enough and not turn.
What sort of people live about here?
In that direction lives a Hatter.
And in that direction lives a March Hare.
Visit either you like: they're both mad.
Why?
The Hatter worked so much with hat blocks,
that he got absolutely block-headed,
so now his nickname is Blockhatter.
And the March Hare
has gotten absolutely cross-eyed.
I mean, from the March sun.
But I don't want to go among mad people.
Oh, you can't help that. We're all mad here.
I'm mad. You're mad.
Would you please not vanish so suddenly, sir?
All right.
Well... I've often seen a cat without a grin,
but a grin without a cat!
It's the most curious thing I ever saw.
She had not gone much farther before
she saw the house of the March Hare.
At the table, the March Hare
and the Blockhatter were having tea.
A Dormouse was sitting
between them, fast asleep.
- No room! No room!
- There's plenty of room!
Have some wine.
I don't see any wine.
Of course you don't! There isn't any.
Then it wasn't very civil of you to offer it.
It wasn't very civil of you to sit down
without being invited.
This table is laid
for a great many more than three.
Would it be better
if there were more of us and fewer cups?
You should say what you mean.
I do. At least I mean what I say.
That's the same thing.
Not the same thing a bit!
You might just as well say that “I see what I eat”
is the same thing as “I eat what I see”.
I think you are just wasting time.
If you knew Time as well as I do,
you wouldn't talk about wasting it.
Of course, of course. I quite agree with you.
I dare say you never even spoke to him!
Perhaps not, but I know
I have to beat time when I learn music.
He won't stand beating!
Yes. We quarreled with Time.
It's always six o'clock now.
And it's always tea-time.
We even have no time
to wash the cups between whiles.
It's the stupidest tea-party
l ever was at in all my life.
I'd better go quickly to the garden.
Open it!
Would you tell me why
you're painting those roses?
You see, Miss, this here ought
to have been a white rose-tree,
and we put a red one by mistake.
If the Queen was to find out,
we shall all have our heads cut off.
“What a cardtege!” thought Alice.
The word seemed to sound wrong,
but she didn't know how to correct it.
Perhaps she, too, ought to lie down
on her face before this grand procession?
But Alice could not remember any such rule.
What would be the use of a procession if people
had to lie face down, so they could not see it?
What is this?
- Your Majesty, they wanted...
- I see. Off with their heads!
Don't be afraid. You shan't be beheaded.
Are their heads off?
Their heads are gone, Your Majesty!
That's right.
- Can you play croquet?
- Yes!
Get to your places!
Off with her head!
Off with his head!
Off with that head, too!
They're dreadfully fond
of beheading people here.
The great wonder is,
that there's anyone left alive!
How are you getting on?
Who are you talking to?
It's a friend of mine, a Cheshire Cat.
Allow me to introduce it.
I don't like the look of it.
However, it may kiss my hand if it likes.
Thank you, I'd rather not.
Executioner, come here!
Off with his head!
I can't cut off a head
unless there is a body to cut it off from.
Anything that has a head can be beheaded!
I'll think about what I shall do with you.
And he will be tried
by the Royal Court of Justice!
♪ The hands are given not for mischief, ♪
Screenplay:
Ye. Zagdansky
Lyrics:
V. Levin
♪ Without them life'd be horrid. ♪
Consultant:
N. Demurova
♪ What shall we slap our forehead with ♪
Director:
Ye. Pruzhansky
♪ If a fly lands on the forehead? ♪
Art Directors:
I Smirnova, H. Umansky
Camera:
A. Mukhin
♪ Another matter is your head. ♪
Composer:
Ye. Ptichkin
♪ Without it you'd only do better. ♪
Sound:
I. Moizhes
Animators:
N. Marchenkova, M. Titov
N. Churilova, A. Pedan
♪ It can't be used to cut your bread, ♪
♪ Or drive in nails for that matter. ♪
Voices:
M. Neolova, A. Schirwindt
R. Plyatt, A. Burmistrov
♪ Some people's heads have no stuffing, ♪
Voices:
T. Vasilyeva, G. Kishko
L. Ignatenko, M. Schwidler
♪ And others' fooled, abused. ♪
Featured music by:
O. Respighi and L. Boccherini
♪ But it's clearly not for nothing ♪
Editor:
S. Kutsenko
♪ That no one wants to lose it. ♪
Executive Producer:
Ye. Dubenko
♪ But it's clearly not for nothing ♪
♪ That no one wants to lose it. ♪
End of Part 2
© Kiev Popular Science Film Studio 1981
On commission of the USSR State Committee
of TV and Radio Broadcasting
KIEVNAUCHFILM
Artistic Animation Association
Based on the fairy tale by Lewis Carroll
ALICE IN WONDERLAND
Part 3
Before the court building
where Alice ran to, a crowd was gathering.
Make way for the Duchess!
You dear thing, you can't think
how glad I am to make your acquaintance.
She is not mean at all.
Why is the Rabbit so afraid of her?
She must be so nice because of the doughnut.
Doughnuts make people sweet-tempered.
I seem to have found a new kind of rule!
Vinegar makes people sour.
Camomile makes them bitter.
Pepper makes them hot-tempered.
I only wish people knew that!
Then they wouldn't be so
stingy about doughnuts.
You're lost in thoughts, my dear,
and that makes you forget to talk.
I can't tell you just now what the moral
of that is, but I shall remember it in a bit.
Perhaps it hasn't one.
Everything's got a moral,
if only you can find it.
Flamingoes and mustard both bite.
And the moral of that is:
birds of a feather flock together.
Mustard is a mineral, I think.
Right, as usual.
What a clear way of putting things!
Of course, it is a mineral!
There's a large mustard-mine near here.
And the moral of that is:
The more there is of mine,
the less there is of yours.
Oh, I know! Mustard is a vegetable.
How fond she is of finding morals in things!
I quite agree with you.
And the moral of that is:
Be what you would seem to be.
Or if you'd like it put more simply -
Never imagine yourself not to be otherwise
than what it might appear to others
that what you were or might
have been was not otherwise
than what you had been would have
appeared to them to be otherwise.
Silence in the court!
Alice had never been in a court of justice
before, but she read about it.
She was quite pleased to find that she
knew the name of nearly everything here.
“Those must be the jurors,” thought Alice.
“And that's the judge, because of his great wig.”
The Duchess saw the Queen
and began to tremble.
And in a moment, she was gone.
Herald, read the accusation!
The Queen of Hearts, she made some tarts,
All on a summer day.
The Knave of Hearts, he stole those tarts,
And took them quite away!
Consider your verdict.
Not yet, not yet!
There's a great deal to come before that.
The Rabbit got scared of his own audacity.
To say “no“ to the Queen herself!
First witness!
I beg pardon, your Majesty, I...
I'm a poor man.
Give your evidence, and don't be nervous,
or I'll have you executed on the spot.
- I hadn't finished my tea when...
- Get to the point.
I'm a poor man.
I keep thinking of the bygone days.
Days.
Dumb like a dunce.
Perhaps, we shall make him dance?
Well, it's a play upon words.
Next witness, the March Hare!
I didn't say anything.
He denies it, doesn't he?
I didn't think anything.
Suppress him!
Alice had read in the newspapers:
“The attempts at resistance were suppressed.”
Now she understood what it meant.
At this moment,
Alice felt a very curious sensation.
She realized she was growing larger again.
Alice decided to remain where she was
as long as there was room for her.
Next witness, Alice!
Here!
Oh, I beg your pardon!
What do you know about this business?
Nothing.
What? Nothing whatever?
Nothing whatever.
That's very important.
Unimportant, your Majesty means, of course.
Unimportant, of course, I meant.
Unimportant, of course, unimportant.
Important... Unimportant...
Unimportant... Important...
There's more evidence to come yet,
please your Majesty.
This paper has just been picked up.
What's in it?
I haven't read it yet, but it seems to be
a letter written by the prisoner to somebody.
Who is it directed to?
It isn't directed at all.
There's nothing written on the outside.
Is it in the prisoner's handwriting?
No, and that's the queerest thing about it.
The Knave must have imitated
somebody else's hand.
Please your Majesty,
I didn't write it.
There's no name signed at the end.
That's even worse.
You must have meant some mischief,
or else you'd have signed your name
like an honest man.
That proves his guilt.
It proves nothing of the sort!
Why, you don't even know what it's about.
Read it.
Of course, she has the fits of rave
Whenever she gets bolder.
But, see, it's not altogether safe
To cut straight from the shoulder.
To cut from the shoulder?
Have I ever cut straight from the shoulder?
Never!
I cut off heads from the shoulders,
never from one shoulder!
It's a pun!
Let the jury consider their verdict.
No, no! Sentence first.
Verdict afterwards.
Stuff and nonsense!
- Hold your tongue!
- I won't!
Off with her head!
Who cares for you?
You're nothing but a pack of cards!
“What a curious dream I've had,” thought Alice,
and she ran home, not to be late for tea.
In the future, she would be a grown woman
and, keeping the simple and loving
heart of her childhood,
would tell other children about Wonderland
and remember her own childhood
and the happy summer days.
♪ What kind of games in her homestead ♪
Screenplay:
Ye. Zagdansky
♪ Does a Queen play all day long? ♪
Lyrics:
V. Levin
♪ She never tires of cutting the heads ♪
Consultant:
N. Demurova
♪ Of the people who come along. ♪
Director:
Ye. Pruzhansky
Art Directors:
I. Smirnova, H. Umansky
Camera:
A. Mukhin
♪ By executing her loyal men ♪
Composer:
Ye. Ptichkin
♪ She's ready to keep the peace. ♪
Sound:
I. Moizhes
♪ But what's the use when all her servants ♪
Animators:
N. Marchenkova, M. Titov
N. Churilova, A. Pedan
♪ Are headless as it is? ♪
Voices:
M. Neolova, R. Zelonaya
R. Plyatt, A. Burmistrov
♪ And I shall tell her outright: ♪
Voices:
T. Vasilyeva, Ye. Paperny
G. Kishko
♪ I don't fear you at all! ♪
Featured music by:
O. Respighi and L. Boccherini
♪ I know I'm just sleeping at night ♪
Editor:
S. Kutsenko
♪ And you're my dream, nothing more! ♪
Executive Producer:
Ye. Dubenko
♪ I know I'm just sleeping at night ♪
End of Part 3
♪ And you're my dream, nothing more! ♪
© Kiev Popular Science Film Studio 1981