Downloaded from
YTS.MX
Official YIFY movies site:
"REFLECTIONS OF A BLENDER"
I can't stay silent
like I used to.
Damned fever that keeps
me away from the fridge...
the stove,
the sink, the clock...
from all these objects
that work machine-like...
as men like to say.
And don't care
or even know that...
they are called objects,
stuff, kitchen appliances.
And what about me?
Appliance and what else?
Still blades...
but inside me,
a flow of ideas, thoughts...
sensations, grinding
and tearing at my silence...
spinning and crushing
like sharp edges.
Blender and witness...
grinding machine
and accomplice...
to all the events that
altered the life...
of the owners of this house...
and my condition as object.
- I'm leaving.
- Good luck.
- God's will be done.
- Amen.
My husband's been
missing eight days.
He left one morning
to go to the market...
and never came back.
Does your husband
have any mental problems?
No, sir.
Onofre is a normal man...
healthy, hardworking.
He's never been gone
for so long.
- How old is your husband?
- 67.
- Any children?
- No, sir.
Has he had any disagreements...
with anyone
in the past few days?
No, thank God.
The whole neighborhood
was fond of him...
He was respected at work.
Everyone's worried about
his disappearance.
- Ms...
- Elvira.
Ms. Elvira. Have you considered
the possibility that he has left?
Left how?
You mean to say
that he abandoned me?
Unfortunately, it is not
altogether impossible.
I have seen a number
of such cases.
Lieutenant, we've been
married for over 40 years.
Lots of harmony and
tenderness between us.
Why would Onofre leave me?
Another woman, for instance.
No! The police
can't even think that.
Onofre is a faithful husband.
He's not that kind of man,
thank God!
Well, Ms. Elvira,
I'll file a report...
and assign a detective
to the case.
But I can tell you this:
the first suspect
on his disappearance...
is you.
I wonder what happened.
The hand on the clock has
turned a few times...
and she hasn't come back yet.
Maybe she
can deceive the police...
and calm herself down.
What happened?
The worst.
Did you go to the station?
Yes.
They suspected me.
How come?
Fuinha!
I didn't like that
Fuinha character.
- Why not?
- I didn't like his nose.
He looks like a snoop.
With a thin nose.
Dangerous.
Once I left,
he followed me around.
Is it normal to follow
a person right away...
Who knows...
or did he suspect
me from beginning?
Where did you go?
First I went to the church.
Didn't you say you couldn't
face the image of Christ?
I prayed with closed eyes.
But I thought God could
see inside people.
Shut up.
What do you know
about religion? Shut up.
We all pray any way we can.
And then I went shopping
for these fruit.
You made thing
too easy for him.
You could buy fruit
some other day!
Why didn't you come
straight home?
Enough talking,
you're too nosy.
Get to work!
What are you doing?
It's been days since I've had an
avocado shake.
Elvira.
I don't feel like
blending now.
Why not?
I don't feel well.
Leave the avocado
for some other time.
They might see your blade.
You look like a weapon,
not a blender.
You're the one who
made a weapon of me.
And now, they'll blame me.
Don't be afraid.
Just help me.
- Haven't I done all I can?
- Yes, but I need a bit more.
- And then, Elvira?
- Then what?
When it's over,
what will you do with me?
Nothing; you'll go on
working as a blender.
I don't want you to break me.
I won't break you, silly!
Nutty blender!
Let's grind!
Get to work!
Quit snarling.
Bastard!
You're no good anymore.
Too noisy.
Watch it, you, bastard.
Ok. Now you're singing,
aren't you?
That's it. I like that.
Sing my little bird.
Why can't you always
work like this?
Bastard.
You sing when you want to...
and when you don't,
you snarl!
And when you're up to it,
you can grind perfectly.
That I do well;
shakes are my specialty.
You've gotta grind whatever
I put in there, got it?
I did, Elvira.
I ground what you asked me.
But you neighed like a horse.
The neighbors must have heard you.
- It wasn't easy, Elvira.
- Stop yelling.
Then stop pointing fingers.
I did my best.
I'll die repeating that.
You find it disgusting?
Doesn't the shake look tasty?
Your stomach's been
empty for too long.
Go on. Drink a little.
Elvira. Take a sip.
Go on.
That's it.
Drink up.
What's the matter?
What's this taste
you put in the shake?
I put the taste you gave me.
I put in avocado,
milk and sugar.
You gave me something rotten.
You taste that in everything.
The water doesn't
taste like this.
Yesterday you said the banana
and the orange had it.
And the bread, too.
So, it's not me, you're the
one tasting it everywhere.
Don't you try to trick me,
when you least expect it, I'll...
- What?
- Watch it.
It's Fuinha!
Don't panic.
It may be a neighbor.
I'll throw it away.
No, Elvira, don't do that.
What about the taste of death?
There's no such taste.
What if it's Fuinha?
Elvira, the house is clean
and you're alone. Go on!
- Elvira!
- May Jesus be with me.
- Amen.
- I'm coming.
Go, Elvira. Go!
Hi, Ms. Elvira.
Long time no see.
Has the old man come back?
Nothing so far.
- I have news.
- A letter?
No. May I come in?
It won't take long.
I need to tell you something.
Oh, I miss Mr. Onofre.
So, you fixed the blender?
Avocado, yum!
I don't know it's ok,
the avocado might be spoiled.
Let's have a taste of it,
so we know for sure.
Your shakes are delicious.
You mind if I sit?
I've been walking.
Drink it slowly,
it's the only glass.
The best shake in town.
What do you have
to tell me?
I don't mean to snoop into
other people's lives...
Mr. Onofre was such
a good man, wasn't he?
Despite his favorite
soccer team.
Cut to the chase.
I'd rather deliver one thousand
letters than tell you this.
Do you really have
something to say?
I do.
Mr. Onofre...
He has... or had...
an affair.
- What?
- An affair.
Another woman, you understand?
I saw it.
What did you see?
What other woman?
It's not like me to meddle
in people's lives.
I was passing by the
hospital and saw him.
That's a lie.
Onofre wasn't that kind of man!
I saw how anguished you were
and decided to tell you.
She's a nurse...
I shouldn't even have said that...
So I talked to her...
and she hadn't heard
from him in two weeks.
So I decided to come here...
the old man has vanished,
he's really gone.
- Get out!
- I only wanted to help.
I'll file a complaint
at the postal company!
Go to the police
before it's too late!
What the heck?!
It's not like him
to nose around.
But he knew who she was,
her job, her workplace.
How terrible!
Even the mailman knew it.
How can a man
be so disrespectful?
What about me?
How about me all this time?
Disgrace.
Stop that.
Stop it!
In this house things work
the way they like!
You want to drip?
So drip.
Let water out the pipe.
That's it.
Flood it, flood it all.
Premium eggs on sale.
Potatoes. Onions. Garlic.
Oranges. Lime. Quayle eggs.
Bananas. Tomatoes.
Sweet Potatoes.
Assorted sweets.
Things have changed
in the past few days.
It's unusually
tense around here.
I'm never at ease
when she's awake.
And even when she sleeps
my thoughts don't rest.
Why did they do this to me?
What makes my engine...
understand human feelings?
Particularly of the people
in this house?
I must have been
happy before...
because I can't
remember how it was.
Engines have no memory.
Nor do they need it...
is already a form of happiness.
Blenders are born in factories
and die in junkyards.
It's a simple story,
a straight line.
We're useful as long as we work.
Replaced when we break down.
It's not the same
for men, though.
From what I've seen,
they don't know...
where they come from,
where they're going...
why they're born,
why they live or die.
This life full of doubt
they call "conscious life".
And it's that same consciousness
they gave me...
when they replaced some
parts of my mechanism.
I don't know if it all
happened slowly...
or suddenly,
by simply changing a screw.
I don't know.
I doubt my first moments
as much as any human.
Assembly line,
mass production...
everything seems
to start there.
And if that's the start
of an object...
why can't it be
the start of people too?
One of the first
events I remember...
it happened when I was still
a regular blender...
a mere appliance.
What the hell?
A piece of iron in the shake.
- Iron?
- A blade.
What if I'd swallowed it?
It's a piece of the blender.
Watch out! You might send
someone six feet under!
I was placed in a corner.
It was the first time
I heard perfectly well...
- what people were saying.
- I made a choice...
that I'd represent Cain.
Before the Creator?
Before the Creator
and before his creatures.
The word is our key instrument.
I was there all afternoon.
The sound of the human voice
entranced me.
I observed people and
their conversations.
But everything cleared up
both inside and outside me...
when they put
in the new blade.
It looks like a scorpion.
Looks like a weapon.
Ugly beast.
Back to the counter.
This one will have last
'til the end, right?
Another five months?
Seven, Onofre, seven.
What'll happen to us?
Same as always.
If anyone asked me,
I'd say the change of blades...
made me the happiest
appliance in the world.
I felt strong and sturdy
as never before.
Went back to work
with renewed enthusiasm.
It was like coming
out of the factory.
Those were the best
seven months of my life!
But they went by much,
much too quickly.
The china, the coffeemaker
and other appliances were boxed.
I was placed in a spot
that at first seemed uncomfortable.
But I soon realized that I couldn't
wish for a better seat.
I marveled at
the busy streets.
That world was
stunning to me.
Created by mighty beings.
I looked at people's faces
on the sidewalk...
crossing the streets,
driving their fantastic cars...
and I felt chosen by the gods for
an unforgettable adventure.
And then... I saw the fountain.
The water was rising as if
trying to reach the sun.
Premium eggs on sale.
Directly from the farm...
- How's everything?
- Fine.
- Have anything for me today?
- Sadly, nothing.
- Forgot all about me.
- We'd never forget you.
- What did you want with him?
- A letter.
You flirt with everyone,
don't you?
Come on, baby.
- Bye.
- Go to work now. Bye.
How are you, boss?
I don't boss, I beg.
Any news?
Nothing yet. If I hear about a job,
I'll let you know.
- Any news for me?
- Nothing yet, Mr. Onofre.
No problem. Thank you.
At first I missed
the smoothie shop.
I enjoyed the variety
of customers...
new faces, different topics,
other voices.
Now it was just me
and the housewife.
And sometimes
the next-door neighbor...
who always chose
the same subject.
- You like the manioc?
- It's great.
The fresher, the tastier.
I saw on TV that eating entire
grapes is good for you.
Is it?
- And makes you want it.
- Want what?
It, Ms. Elvira.
Not working?
It's a bad plug.
Bad blender.
Has a mind of its own.
Jeez!
I like to tear the pulp
of fruit and vegetables...
and stick my blade
into words and ideas.
Everything turns when they
switch me on and speed me up.
I work in 3 speeds:
1,2 and 3.
I know people who hate
numbers and don't get math.
Not me. I get it very well.
Grindingly well.
1,2,3.
Grinding is thinking.
Thinking is grinding.
I sold the cooler,
the coffeemaker...
and the small blender.
Onofre, did you have to?
Don't you think?
Four months and not a penny.
What about us?
How are we going to live?
Empty stomach,
no water, no light?
Why didn't you sell this blender?
It is a piece of junk.
I wanted to leave
you the best.
It used to be the best.
It's been rubbish for a while.
Didn't tell you this old thing's crazy?
I didn't see you get up today.
Lots of housework to do.
Help me!
My leg hurts!
Help me with the pillow, will you?
Straighten it out.
- Better?
- Yes.
Did you sleep well?
Sort of. How was your first day
as night guard?
I took a whole pot of coffee.
It's hard to be bound
to this bed.
Think of something to do.
With a broken leg?
Didn't you use to stuff animals?
That was ages ago,
I was just a girl.
You made some money with
that taxi... taxi...
Taxidermy.
Go back to stuffing
and I'll try to sell it.
All right.
Before bed,
can you make me breakfast?
With everything you deserve.
Easy.
- Hold on to me.
- Ok.
- Happy?
- It's beautiful.
Do you think I'll remember?
- Learn again.
- Practicing, right?
I'm going to bed.
When you get up,
It'll be ready.
- That quick?
- Yeah.
Elvira.
Hey! Over here.
- It's me!
- Who?
Me, Elvira.
The blender.
If it's restless spirit, I'll have
a mass prayed for you, ok?
That's senility, Elvira.
Maybe it is.
Or you're pulling my leg.
Yeah, sure.
Time to go.
Careful or the blender
will catch you.
Stop that.
Elvira.
Don't be frightened.
It's me again.
The blender.
- You...?
- Yeah. It's me.
I would love to talk.
Share some thoughts.
I think I can... at least... try.
Do you want to?
I'm going insane.
- Or is this senility?
- What's senility?
Senility is this.
Me, talking to a machine.
Chatting with a blender.
I like that.
Yeah. Senility.
...that's right, Elvira.
I like senility.
Of course you like it.
It's why you're
talking to me.
And I listen. And answer!
- Right?
- If you think so, then yes.
Elvira, you have lovely teeth,
you know?
- What?
- I like teeth.
I like everything that cuts.
I have good teeth too, don't I?
- No, you've got blades.
... that cut.
They really do.
You look like a scorpion.
What's a scorpion?
It's an animal that stings
and poisons the blood.
It kills the person.
Kill? What's to kill?
It's to send someone
six feet under.
Six feet under what?
What a funny expression.
Cool. Six feet under.
- Ms. Elvira. I'm coming in.
- Come in, honey.
What's that, Ms. Elvira?
- Never seen a stuffed animal before?
- No.
Not up close.
it's weird.
- Disgusting?
- Not disgusting. Just weird.
I've done it since
I was a child.
To each their own, right?
I bet you're tired
of sitting there all day.
A person's talking to me,
another comes...
the person turns her back on me,
without even a goodnight.
Old senile woman. How rude!
- Is this ok, Ms. Elvira?
- Great.
I'm lucky you have
strong arms to help me.
Mary, mother of God.
Don't mention
"arms" to me today.
You remember my boss
at the store?
Your boss?
The one with the hairy arms?
The very one.
Something happened...
between us today
that was weird.
He came to me with
a glass of water...
his hairy arm sticking out,
just the way I like it.
I went crazy, Ms. Elvira.
- Did that go any further?
- No.
No. It made me shiver,
that was all.
Milena, stay away from that arm.
Ms. Elvira, I swear to you
I want nothing with him.
It was just that chill.
Nothing else.
What?
Come on, give me a break.
Ah, Milena.
Can I hold it?
You're a real artist, Ms. Elvira.
Later you can
remove the needles.
And leave it to dry in the sun.
My mother will love it.
- This cat was your mother's?
- Yeah. Mauro.
He died and I asked
her to stuff it.
Mom won't believe it.
Unbelievable,
stuffing mummy's kitten!
Why don't you learn it?
That's disgusting!
Any money in it,
Ms. Elvira?
Some change.
Rabbits sell well.
Hello, folks.
- What's up?
- Hello, Mr. Onofre.
What's wrong, dear?
- It's over.
- What do you mean?
Some city officials took
away the animals.
- The two ducks?
- Both. They said...
it's illegal to sell animals
dead or alive.
If they catch me again
I'll go to jail.
The well has dried.
I was just mentioning
I was making some change.
No more stuffed animals.
Why go to the movies?
So you can have
a fit of jealousy?
You were staring
at that bearded guy.
Bearded who?
Don't be coy.
The bearded fatso.
- That hairy monkey?
- That's the one.
You were drooling
all over him.
Drooling?
Over that bushy face?
You're a piece of work.
Wellington, you know
I don't like hairy men.
I'll tell you one thing.
If you cheat on me...
I'll use a gun
the old fashioned way.
Gun? You know
the kind of weapon I want?
The magazine?
The ammunition?
- Tell me, pumpkin pie.
- I'm driving.
Pumpkin pie with a smooth,
smooth body.
Open fire tonight, baby?
Maybe a little open fire.
- Good morning.
- Morning.
- Remember me?
- Yes, sir.
- I promised you a visit.
- Yes, sir. Come on in.
- Anybody home?
- No, sir.
Any sign of the husband?
No, sir.
He left everything here.
You mean he vanished with
no belongings?
Only what he was wearing.
This is his work outfit.
Tell me something.
Did he drink?
Just a little beer
on Sundays.
I see. But where?
And with whom?
With his pals at the pub...
or the next-door neighbor,
but he never got drunk.
You may close it now.
I'm doing a routine inspection.
Don't touch any clothes.
Leave everything as it is.
Not even mine?
Your clothes you may touch,
of course.
But only yours.
Not the victim's.
- Victim?
- Your husband was murdered.
Don't you take my hope away!
What's that?
Is anyone else here?
It's just the blender.
It switches on by itself.
- By itself?
- Wacked out machine.
Don't turn it off.
Hold on.
You mean he turns
on by itself?
It kind of works
when it wants to.
We used it
at the smoothie shop.
What's in it?
Beets.
Blood-colored, eh?
Beets are red, aren't they?
May I turn it off?
There, old thing.
Calm down.
Excuse me.
Do you drink pure blood?
What do you mean?
Look... Doesn't it look like blood?
Do I look like a vampire?
You just like the
color of blood?
Why do you talk
about blood so much?
Why?
Does the word bother you?
"Blood". You bothered?
- Who isn't bothered by blood?
- Murderers.
You certainly know
those better than I.
Exactly. That's why they don't
escape me, get it?
I can smell them.
Drink it.
- What?
- A drink of blood. Drink it.
Leave my beets alone, sir.
Drink up a little blood, ma'am.
When you came in
I was making soup.
May I carry on in peace,
please, Detective?
Drink up half a glass of this...
red liquid, better?
I recognize a murderer's face when
they intake the color of blood.
There.
Any blood on my face?
No, but you drank too quickly.
Straight down the throat.
Drink it slowly.
Gulp by gulp. Slowly.
Leave the blood
on your tongue a while.
Beets are sweet as blood,
aren't they?
It needs a pinch of salt.
I hadn't seasoned the broth.
- Moist soil, Ms. Elvira.
- It's my garden, sir.
- It's been recently watered.
- I water it every day.
I will have it dug
six feet under.
And who will pay for
the damage?
I've seen cases like this,
Ms. Elvira.
The victim buried
in his own backyard.
I'll send the bill
to the Lieutenant.
One buck for each
ruined vegetable.
The police has
full authority.
To investigate, not to
wreck private property.
Who knows how badly
the victim was wrecked!
You get shivers
every time I say "victim".
I do?
You get speechless,
dead silent.
It's because this suspicion...
Go on?
If only you knew
what I want to say.
Just get it off your chest,
Ms. Elvira.
You can stick this suspicion
where the sun doesn't shine!
You can't arrest me
without evidence.
We each have our own
delights, ma'am.
This is mine.
Cuffing away the suspect.
You know why?
If you slay, I'll make you pay.
Keep that in mind!
Fuinha is a madcap.
Everyone has their own method.
This is mine.
Take it easy, Fuinha.
I'm taking it easy, sir.
I catch the smell
of blood, get it?
It's my sixth sense.
A murderers' sweat changes.
The more they try to hide it...
the more I sense the blood.
This old lady spilled
her husband's blood.
The stench is coming
out through her pores.
You said the same
about that other lady.
The doctor's widow.
Stench, pores...
talk about a slip-up!
Only God is infallible, pal.
And not always.
That's why I tell you.
Slow down, Fuinha.
Easy on the shock treatment.
No sweat, boss.
You can count on me.
I'll find the corpse.
Wellington can get
you a lawyer, Ms. Elvira.
What's this cop thinking?
That he can wave handcuffs
in your face like that?
He gave me the creeps.
I almost had a fit.
Relax, Ms. Elvira,
have some tea.
I have to go.
- Godspeed.
- Same to you.
What did that busybody want?
Why did you have to
turn on right then?
I got nervous.
Couldn't help it.
You almost ruined everything.
What about you and your beets?
It was the only thing
in the fridge.
Justice be done.
You tap danced around him.
You think?
It's fair to say you tap
danced around him...
and committed
the perfect crime.
Both of us did.
You were a great accomplice.
Thank you.
As a matter of fact,
I was always an accomplice.
Even back at the
smoothie shop.
Actually, I don't know
if I was accomplice or a victim.
What I do know is that people
say things meaning one thing...
But their attitudes
mean the opposite.
When they're interested,
they're full of pretty words...
But when they are contested,
there comes ingratitude.
There comes poison.
You going out?
Overtime, Elvira.
Overtime.
There's no time for us anymore.
No more Saturday,
no more Sunday...
and now no more
Monday either.
Too much work is
better than no work.
I bought some
chicken for lunch.
But you'll eat at work, right?
Good news.
I found a buyer
for blabbermouth.
The owner of the bar by my job.
I told him I fixed it...
and he wants to see it.
- Don't sell it, please.
- How come?
At home it's still
good for something.
That's precisely why we haven't
bought a new one.
He's growing on me.
- I'm going.
- Take care.
That hurt me deeply.
I left with a complete
sense of abandonment.
A true piece of junk.
But one thing is now clear to me...
human feelings are like
a double-edged blade...
one knife smoothes your vanity
the other cuts into your pride.
Back with the blabbermouth?
I thought you'd bring a new blender.
When I get my pay,
I'll buy a new one.
And why the triple shift?
Something wrong
with the other guards.
There's a swap this week.
Where did you get that tan?
Day shifts are sunny...
the night doesn't
give you a tan.
I'm very tired.
I made you some cabbage soup.
I had a snack at the factory.
I'm tired, not hungry.
I'll take a shower
and go straight to bed.
This shift change throws me off.
Can't rely on the clock,
it's crazy...
Didn't even bother
getting me out.
She laid anguished in bed.
Well deserved,
I must say.
So they didn't want
you at the bar?
You piece of junk.
Doesn't matter.
You're still useful here.
Not even with your iron tongue
did they want you.
That's aging for you.
Old Thing.
What kind of test
did they put you through?
Sand and oil.
What did they think you were?
A construction tool?
You poor thing.
Why are you quiet
like a rock?
Have you lost your ability
to talk, to understand?
Jammed for good.
I saw the ocean.
- At last you're talking.
- Yeah. I saw the waves.
- What?
- I didn't like it at all.
Where did you see the ocean?
Too much water. Too noisy.
I prefer the fountain.
What's this about the ocean?
You've never seen the sea?
What's this about?
Never been where?
Guarujá.
Who took you to Guarujá?
The bar owner?
Bar? What bar?
I don't belong in bars.
What the hell in this?
Working, it must sound
like a jackhammer.
Gimme banana and milk.
Looks like a Russian submarine.
You'll pay by the dose, guys.
A dose each.
Here goes nothing.
What the hell?
Is this outlet working?
Of course it is,
the TV was here.
How did you
end up at the beach?
Onofre threw me in the
backseat of the car.
What car?
The car that took us
to Guarujá, of course.
- Whose car?
- The lady's.
What lady?
Spit it out. What lady? What car?
- If you want to know, go there.
- Go where?
To Santos.
They went there today.
Listen, Onofre left for work...
Yesterday Guarujá.
Today, Santos.
Tomorrow, Peruíbe,
then, Praia Grande.
Four days at the beach.
When parting, she said,
"beach tomorrow, honey?"
And he replied,
"beach tomorrow, doll. "
- He isn't in today?
- He'll be out 'til Thursday.
- Who's this?
- A friend of the family's.
- Do you have his house number?
- Yes.
I've tried, nobody answers.
I'll try again. Thank you.
This is not happening.
It's a nightmare.
I'm dreaming.
This isn't real.
It can't be.
It can't be true!
There was no beach, no car,
no Guarujá, no honey, no doll.
Someone will have
to prove it.
I need proof...
I need proof!
Where's the evidence
that you exist?
That you talk, feel...
React like a person?
It's him.
So, those were the so-called guts.
Piece of cake.
Piece of cake, of course.
Heart, stomach, bowels.
Let's see some bones!
Bones are the tough part.
What's the matter with bones?
You'll see.
What's the ice for?
You don't like it?
They're ok.
- Then stop complaining.
- I'm not complaining, Elvira.
I'm only trying
to understand.
Ice and bones are a good match.
Both are white and hard.
- I still don't get it.
- You'll get it now.
Grind.
Premium eggs on sale.
Potatoes. Onions. Garlic.
Oranges. Lime.
Quayle eggs.
Bananas. Tomatoes.
Sweet Potatoes.
Yes?
Are you aware of any quibbles
between them recently?
- Was he rude, for example?
- No.
Quite the opposite.
He treated her like a queen.
I've also heard old Onofre
was a bit of a lady's man.
- Did he ever come on to you?
- Never! No way.
He was never fresh with me.
You never caught
him looking...
at your...
or at your...?
My what, sir?
No offense, ma'am.
I'm investigating!
I meant your legs,
your knees, get it?
He peeped at my legs
with eyes like this.
You don't say!
He asked me
"what do you think of oral sex?"
Christ! This man must be denounced!
That's harassment.
I replied, "sex to me is a relationship
of complete freedom".
If the partner wants and deserves it,
he takes what he gives.
He opened his little eye
at me, like that...
got up, put his hand in his pocket.
He was totally aroused!
I thought he'd grab
me right there...
and spread my legs.
That thin little nose...
like a penis stuck to his face.
How long have you
known them?
About five years. Since I
started delivering mail there.
I heard you're
close to Elvira.
I also heard sometimes
you suck on her shakes.
Yeah. Sometimes
she's kind enough to offer.
She only gives you that sort
of shake or other types too?
Come on. Ms. Elvira is a lady.
I call her auntie.
Funny. I know a fellow who
called his neighbor "granny"...
and she sat on his face.
Tell me...
Onofre was kind of naughty,
wasn't he?
Tell me the truth.
No. We only talked soccer.
But I did see him
at the hospital once.
I was around and I saw it.
It was really him.
He was with a lady.
Excited, see?
- So was she.
- I'm understanding...
I recently told Ms. Elvira.
I knew there was something
fishy here.
That's it.
I had four days off...
because I had
doubled my shift.
He did the same
thing at his job.
So, you arranged that?
Yes, so we could have
a small honeymoon.
You know what I mean.
How did you meet him?
His company sent him to the
hospital where I work as a nurse.
Twelve by eight.
Your blood pressure's fine.
That's nice.
- Let's check your heart now.
- Yes, let's.
Inhale. Exhale. Inhale.
Inhale again.
Exhale slowly.
That's it. Again.
Inhale.
Exhale.
That's it.
I think my pressure's rising!
So, the old man whiffed
you right in.
I am very sensitive
in that area.
But it was only physical
in the beginning.
Later a great love ensued.
He was gonna leave
his wife for me.
I'm sure he wouldn't
vanish like this.
Someone got rid of him.
Either his wife or a hired gun.
I played you for a sucker?
Why didn't you tell me
straight away about the nurse?
Because when
the mailman came by...
I had already been to the station.
Then why not tell me right after?
Because I don't believe it.
That mailman has a big mouth.
Loves to gossip.
I heard that you...
stuff animals.
Yes, sir.
What weapons do you
use to embalm them?
They're instruments
not weapons.
My father was
in the business.
He made this one.
I learned as a little girl.
Tell me something,
Ms. Elvira...
how long did it take you
to embalm your husband?
Please, Detective.
One week?
42 years.
I spent the entire marriage
embalming my husband.
I'm telling you.
Piercing objects
laying around.
Needles, scissors,
a hoe, a hatchet.
A load of weapons, sir.
So, which one did
she use, Fuinha?
Beats me.
The first blow may
have been with the hoe.
The victim in the backyard.
The old man squatting,
gardening.
She comes from behind and
hits him with the hoe.
Get it, Chief?
But don't they
have neighbors?
Sure. A married couple.
By the way, there's
a second theory.
Maybe it wasn't in the yard...
but in the kitchen.
He's there, waiting for supper...
she comes back with
a knife instead a soup.
And then, she chops his
head off. Maybe.
One blow, two three.
But there's also a third theory.
He's asleep...
she grabs her
embalming needles...
tiptoes into
the silent room and...
sticks the needles into
the victim's ears, Chief.
Then, the hatchet.
Then the blender.
She made minced meat
out of her husband...
and got rid of
the body in the blender.
Piece by piece.
Bone by bone.
Is that your conclusion, Fuinha?
Bull's eye, Chief.
Grinding bone in a blender.
Gimme a break.
We're overwhelmed with work...
and you come to me
with this fabrication!
Come in.
I need your honest opinion.
What is it, Milena?
It's nothing serious.
But it's important to me.
Did you know
that celebrities...
not all, but many...
aren't wearing them anymore.
Not wearing what?
- Panties.
- Working with no panties on?
Not to outline the fabric,
you see?
- I don't believe it.
- Oh yes.
- Come on.
- Look now.
Milena!
- Stop it, girl.
- Bye, Ms. Elvira.
I should remember more
about the human body.
Each part is the enemy
of the other parts.
The ears twist
what they hear...
the eyes distort
what they see...
the tongue uses
phrases to seduce...
to befuddle, to better
or worsen things...
according to its mood.
I have no ears, eyes or mouth,
but it's as if I did.
I got this trait from
living with people...
People who gave me
an awareness of life...
but also an awareness
of death.
Now I know what it means
to be "six feet under".
But in spite of all,
if I could choose...
if I could go back to being
a simple kitchen appliance...
insensitive and mute,
I don't know if I'd want to.
Hmm, no, I wouldn't.
To think is addictive,
to feel is like booze...
and all this restless waiting,
filled with passion and fear...
it all that fascinates me.
What fate has in store for me
is a mystery, a threat...
but until then...
as the night presses on...
my screws will sing
their way into the night!
Sing, my little bird!
Sing old gadget, offspring
of both God and...
Satan!
Sing, glorious blender!